Great.
So we build our component which uses props to get data from the parent.
We can then use it in a function as we do here.
Maybe it's a reusable component you want to use in multiple places and in each place it gets different
data.
But of course the type of data should always be equal.
So here where we reworks the name while this will not work if you pass in a number or a boolean.
It has to be a string.
This component gets.
So in order to make sure we're not getting an error due to someone passing let's say one year keep the
dynamic binding to pass a number instead of a string.
Well that of course will break the application
as you can tell here because we can't use split on a number.
So in order to prevent this we want to validate the prop's coming in and that can set up validation
here in this prop's array or in this prop's key here on our object prop's can not only be an array if
you want to validate it.
It should be an object.
And there we have as a key or a property name like my name.
And then as a value the type of that.
So that could be of type string to force it to be of type string.
You could also say it can be multiple types.
So since these basically only want to reverse that you could also say this should be of type string
or array.
So we're passing now array of types here.
You can say it can have multiple types multiple types are valid though.
Here I want to revert back to just using the string.
So with this I'm making sure that I'm only getting the data on one I get.
Now what happens if I set up the validation here and pass a one.
Now I've saved this and I opened the console and reload the page here.
You see now I'm getting a warning that the prompt check did fail and the whole component is therefore
not attached like this.
So I'm still getting an error of course because what else should do you just do.
It can prevent me from typing a wrong code there.
But I do get such warnings at development time and thus I recognize that number.
I'm using the wrong property and by adding validation like this I'm making sure that inside of this
component I can be sure that I only get strings because otherwise my application will flow in error
anyways and will give me at development time a warning when setting up the types of properties you can
do even more than just setting the Type Like This.
This could now all to be an object where you set the type of the type key and you could also set required
to true to make sure this is a property which always is a string and it should always be available it
should always be passed if you don't set required.
It would be valid to use your component like this and not pass this name well by setting required to
true.
You're making sure this component may only be used if this component or excuse me if this property is
passed.
So that's in addition when setting up prompt validation to make sure that your component definitely
has what it needs to run optimally.
You can also set a default value to make sure dead.
Well you have something to work with.
Of course default doesn't make sense to Gabr with required because how would you have a default if it's
required anyways.
The default would always get overwritten.
So default would be said to indicate a string some string like Max.
So that now if my remove does my name here and I'm not passing a property I'm still getting Max passed
down there as you can see by the reverse name.
I'll revert this nonetheless.
And if you would have let's say an object or array here.
So if you have type object let's say it doesn't make sense here but if you would have this well then
the default should always be a function which returns the object structure it should have a default
object you want to use like name Max again doesn't make sense for this use case but just to let you
know how that would look like you would use such a function if that is of type Object or array for primitive
types like string boolean and number.
So like string we used before you said it directly to that value you want to use though.
This is how you validate props and how you make sure that the properties the props you're working with
actually have the floor mat.
You need them to have.